Hwayongju, come here.
华永州，你过来。
Yes, recently.
是的，最近。
My home is not very safe
我的家不太安全
How about you starting today?
从今天开始怎么样？
Just go to your eldest lady’s yard and work as a guard.
就去你大小姐的院子里干个门卫就行了。
Remember, you have to be vigilant
记住，你必须保持警惕
yes
是的
great
伟大的
I'll give you this
我给你这个
I am a ginkgo tree in the yard of a large house
我是大房子院子里的一棵银杏树
just come with us
跟我们一起来吧
My name is Tsuiju.
我叫翠菊。
Next month is ancestral rites.
下个月是祭祖仪式。
I would also like to lend some of my manpower to Magistrate Wang Hyeon.
我也愿意借我的一些人力给王贤县长。
Ultimately, we offer incense to our ancestors.
最后，我们给祖先上香。
For safety reasons, mistakes cannot be made
为了安全起见，不能犯错误
understand‥
理解‥
Sir, you are the son of a big princess.
先生，您是一位大公主的儿子。
Moreover, the head family's herbal medicine can be helpful to the people of this city.
而且，本家的草药能够对这座城市的百姓有所帮助。
How many people do you need?
你需要多少人？
just ask
只是问
Well then, I would like to express my gratitude to Magistrate Wang Hyeon.
那么，我向王贤县长表示感谢。
Don't be rude to me.
别对我无礼。
If it wasn't for the Zhong family before
如果不是之前有钟家
People of Huangcheng
皇城人
It has been ruined for a long time by the Ge family who made false claims using scented medicine.
早已被葛家用香药讹传所毁坏了。
What I do is my duty.
我所做的就是我的职责。
At this point
在此刻
The Ge family who ran away
逃跑的葛家
But were they arrested?
但他们被捕了吗？
In the end, the Ge family was ruined because of our Zhong family.
最终，葛家 因为我们钟家而被毁了。
There's bound to be revenge on my mind
我心里一定会报仇
yes‥
是的‥
But in recent years
但近年来
not much movement
没有太大的动作
I think I was scared because I was scared.
我想我之所以害怕是因为我害怕。
secretly hidden
秘密隐藏
That's it
就是这样
Master, don’t worry.
师父，别担心。
I came to take charge of Hwangcheong.
我是来负责黄清的。
I don’t expect anyone in the Ge family to dare to come out again.
我不指望葛家还有人敢再出来。
That's hard for you
这对你来说很难
What did she just say?
她刚刚说什么？
Yesterday my uncle said my bones were too weak.
昨天我叔叔说我的骨头太弱了。
So I decided to start today.
所以我决定从今天开始。
Start exercising well
开始好好锻炼
It's for my body too
也是为了我的身体
Mom, you won't object, right?
妈妈，您不会反对吧？
Many surprises followed.
随之而来的是许多惊喜。
With your current body and bones
以你目前的身体和骨骼
I am afraid that I will not be able to handle the great gift of ancestor worship.
祭祖大礼我怕是扛不住了。
five
五
eight
八
Madam, that's really true...
夫人，确实如此……
Li’s mother, would you like to come and play with us?
李妈妈，你愿意来和我们一起玩吗？
oldest woman
最年长的女人
Madam, please take your time.
女士，请慢一点。
Madam, how do you behave?
女士，你的行为怎么样？
How good is it?
有多好？
Li Mama ‥
李妈妈‥
Stop quickly!
快停下来！
The reasons why my eldest aunt exercised for the past 15 days are as follows.
大姨这15天坚持锻炼的原因如下。
So my food intake doubled compared to before.
所以我的食物摄入量比以前增加了一倍。
Now it really seems to be having some effect.
现在看来确实起到了一些作用。
This dress I made just a few months ago is a little too small.
这件衣服是我几个月前做的，有点太小了。
If you don't know how to compliment someone else, just shut up.
如果你不知道如何赞美别人，那就闭嘴。
oldest woman
最年长的女人
It's time, it's time to go
是时候了，是时候该走了
My uncle is waiting at the door
我叔叔正在门口等着
let's go
我们走吧
kneel down
下跪
hi
你好
increase
增加
goodbye
再见
three prayers
三个祈祷
prosper
繁荣
Gonghyang
公乡
give honor
给予荣誉
Incense offered to ancestors
给祖先烧香
Protect the head of the household
保护户主
-Uncle -Let's go
-叔叔 -我们走吧
Hurry up‥
赶快‥
Teacher, don't be distracted.
老师，别分心。
I'll give this arrow back to you
我会把这个箭头还给你
Come on
快点
Ouch
哎哟
Teacher, you can't show your face.
老师，你不能露脸啊。
The event is almost over, so please be patient a little longer.
活动已经接近尾声了，还请大家再耐心等待。
good
好的
regret
后悔
This life-saving grace
这救命之恩
This is relevant to all subsequent layouts.
这与后续的所有布局相关。
Then I have to catch it today.
那我今天一定要抓住它。
Where are the arrows?
箭头在哪里？
Why hasn't it shown up yet?
怎么还没显示出来？
what's the problem?
有什么问题？
-Protect the family name of the head of the household.
- 保护户主的姓氏。
Please hand over Ge Jiaxiang’s prescription.
请把葛家祥的药方交出来。
walk
走
Hurry up‥
赶快‥
Take a look at this exquisite dress style
来看看这精致的穿衣风格
Must be Mu Yao's number 3 fan.
肯定是慕瑶的三号粉丝了。
stop it
停下来
that's your goal
这就是你的目标
- Why should I listen to you? - Because I did that in my past life.
- 我为什么要听你的？ - 因为我前世就这么做过。
I'm not hurt at all
我根本没有受伤
In my previous life, I will send you to the next life now.
前世的我，现在就送你下辈子。
Madam, are you okay?
女士，您还好吗？
You said you just didn't take advice
你说你只是没有听取建议
Is this good?
这个好吗？
Little brother, there is a future
小兄弟，有未来
-May I ask your name? -My name is Hwa‥
-我可以问你的名字吗？ -我叫华‥
It's over...now it's a waste of time
结束了……现在是浪费时间
longzhou
龙州
I'll give this arrow back to you
我会把这个箭头还给你
i am coming
我来了
Fool, do you have to stand still and block arrows to save someone?
傻瓜，你一定要站着挡箭才能救人吗？
Can't you just push it away?
你就不能把它推开吗？
how… how?
如何… 如何？
how?
如何？
Akian
阿基安
south wind
南风
-Uncle -Lady
- 叔叔 - 女士
- Muyao left it to you - yes
- 慕瑶留给你了 - 是的
oldest woman
最年长的女人
Master, I have obtained the perfume and incense prescription.
师父，香水和香药我已经拿到了。
it's time for us to go
我们该走了
Once discovered, it is difficult to leave.
一旦被发现，就很难离开。
magistrate
地方法官
Dr. Sia
西亚博士
-How is it going? -uncle
-最近好吗？ -叔叔
The great lady's wound was healed.
大夫人的伤已经痊愈了。
This time it's just an injury.
这次只是受了伤。
It's so close to my heart.
它离我的心如此之近。
Are there any more deviations?
还有更多偏差吗？
Even if Hwata is reincarnated
就算华田转世
I'm afraid there's no way to save the day.
恐怕没有办法挽救这一天了。
Now I have no choice but to live a good life
现在我别无选择，只能好好生活
- I don't think it would be difficult to get up - thank you, doctor.
- 我不认为起床会很困难 - 谢谢你，医生。
Mr. Nanfeng, please send the doctor back.
南风先生，请把医生送回来吧。
-Yes - Okay
- 是的 - 好的
south wind
南风
uncle
叔叔
Go to the study room and bring clothes and supplies.
去自习室，带上衣服和用品。
Yes, uncle
是的，叔叔
owner
所有者
Everything has been taken care of.
一切都已处理完毕。
You can blend in with the crowd and leave tomorrow.
你可以混入人群，明天离开。
Over the past few days, Huang Qing has been trying to track down the assassin.
这些天，黄庆一直在努力追查凶手。
Magistrate Wang led everyone to declare martial law.
王县长带领大家宣布戒严。
It's not easy for subordinates either.
对于下属来说也不容易。
Only then did I find the opportunity to go outside.
这时候我才找到机会出去。
Come on
快点
how ridiculous
多么可笑
There are too many people involved in this problem.
涉及这个问题的人太多了。
This caught the old chieftain's attention.
这引起了老酋长的注意。
I have to wait until the owner comes back.
我得等主人回来。
The old master will definitely ask him about this matter.
这件事老爷子肯定会问他的。
So what if I ask?
那如果我问呢？
Do you think you are my father?
你以为你是我的父亲吗？
I'm just willing to start a low-cost medicine business like this.
我只是愿意开始这样的低成本药品业务。
Do you think he doesn't want Jongga's unique perfume recipe?
你认为他不想要宗嘎独特的香水配方吗？
I once accepted the Ge family.
我曾经接受过葛家。
My father didn't even object.
我父亲也没有反对。
Now he has given me full authority over the Wu family’s personnel in many places.
现在他 已经把吴家多处人员的全权交给了我。
Just recognizing my abilities
只是认识到我的能力
Just implicitly agree that I can do anything.
只是含蓄地同意我可以做任何事情。
but
但
The recipe for Gaeummaengwidanhyang obtained this time is fake.
这次获得的Gaeummaengwidanhyang配方是假的。
People who went to Jong's store to inquire
前往Jong店询问的人
nothing was found
什么也没找到
I actually underestimated the head of the clan.
我其实低估了族长。
How dare you undermine their sacrifice?
你怎么敢破坏他们的牺牲？
That person must have already noticed.
那人一定已经注意到了。
However, Hwangseong people are the most superstitious people.
然而，黄城人是最迷信的人。
It is believed that sacrifice is associated with good luck.
人们相信牺牲与好运有关。
Now Jongga’s sacrifice has been ruined.
现在，宗嘎的牺牲已经毁了。
Maybe they want to maintain normal business transactions.
也许他们想维持正常的商业交易。
If so, we become even more inseparable from our medicinal dealers.
如果是这样，我们就更离不开药商了。
This time the owner
这次的主人
In the end, he acted on his own initiative.
最终，他还是主动行动了。
When news leaks out
当消息泄露出去时
I guess it's the old master's side?
估计是老夫子那边吧？
It's difficult to maintain ownership.
维持所有权是很困难的。
The Zhong family is now
钟家如今
I thought the people who did that were their archenemies, the Ge family.
我以为做这事的人就是他们的宿敌葛家。
You don’t have to worry about groundless things.
你不必担心毫无根据的事情。
that‥
那‥
It would be best for us to leave as soon as possible
我们最好尽快离开
you say
你说
Am I late again?
我又迟到了吗？
owner
所有者
The head family's funeral is coming soon.
一家人的葬礼即将举行。
until then
直到那时
I don't mind coming back in public
我不介意在公共场合回来
great
伟大的
you remember
你记得
Our actions sacrificed us this time
这次我们的行为牺牲了我们
The only way to get the fragrant recipe for Gaeummonggyehwan is to catch it.
获得Gaeummonggyehwan的芳香配方的唯一方法就是抓住它。
furthermore
此外
I have no other plans
我没有其他计划
Subordinates will definitely unify their qualities.
属下肯定会统一素质。
no
不
Why is it different from previous plans?
为什么和之前的计划不一样？
me‥
我‥
Akian
阿基安
You finally woke up
你终于醒了
-Me... -Don’t say anything yet.
-我...- 什么也别说。
If the doctor's arrow misses a little,
如果医生的箭稍稍失偏，
I don't think I'll ever see you again
我想我再也见不到你了
-No, I… … - I won't say anything else until I get older.
-不，我…… …… - 在我长大之前我不会再说什么。
What you need most now is a good rest
你现在最需要的是好好休息
-Can you tell me... -I know.
-你能告诉我... -我知道。
Don't worry, A Qian
阿倩别担心
I will never disappoint you from now on.
从现在开始我绝对不会让你失望的。
me‥
我‥
I'll go find a doctor
我去找医生
Nakaya Ake
中谷明
I have something to tell you now
我现在有件事要告诉你
I said it all
我都说了
-What's going on? -When I was young
-发生了什么事？ -当我年轻的时候
The girl who stayed in the temple with you
和你一起住在寺庙里的女孩
Not me
不是我
It's Muyao
是慕瑶啊
What are you talking about?
你在说什么？
Uncle, do you still remember?
叔叔，你还记得吗？
A jade pendant for that woman?
给那个女人的玉佩？
I lied before
我之前撒过谎
My brother took it and lost it.
我哥哥拿走了它，然后又丢了。
But I've seen it with Mu Yao
但我和慕瑶一起看过
furthermore
此外
There is no problem between me and my uncle.
我和我叔叔之间没有任何问题。
There has never been a relationship between husband and wife.
夫妻之间从来就没有过关系。
Before the accident
事故发生前
I was the one who gave the medicine
是我给的药
Because I just noticed
因为我刚刚注意到
Uncle treats Muyao differently.
舅舅对慕瑶不一样。
panic
恐慌
That's why I did something so wrong
这就是为什么我做了如此错误的事
Just to make fun of my uncle
就是为了取笑我叔叔
Only then can she marry Zhongzhai.
只有这样，她才能嫁给中斋。
A walk at the moment when life and death are decided
生与死决定时刻的行走
I just found it
我刚刚找到了
Turns out I was so wrong
原来我错了
I don't expect you to forgive my mistakes
我不指望你能原谅我的错误
I only want you
我只想要你
Please don't involve my family in the future.
以后请不要再连累我的家人了。
you‥
你‥
What exactly do you want to do?
你到底想做什么？
One person's fault is everyone's responsibility
一个人的错是每个人的责任
If you want to divorce me, uncle.
如果你想和我离婚的话，叔叔。
I won't complain either.
我也不会抱怨。
you‥
你‥
Uncle, this…
叔叔，这个……
Sir, my luggage is full. When will I start moving?
先生，我的行李已经满了， 我什么时候开始搬家呢？
no need to move
无需移动
uncle
叔叔
Madam, what did you just say to me?
夫人，您刚才对我说什么？
I'm just telling the truth
我只是说实话
truth?
真相？
But why do I feel like my uncle has become a different person?
可是为什么 我感觉叔叔好像变了一个人呢？
Madam, don’t you know?
夫人，您不知道吗？
Just now when you fell asleep
就在你刚刚睡着的时候
How anxious will the uncle outside the door be?
门外的大叔会有多着急呢？
Take the incense out of this room.
把香带出这个房间。
The smell is dizzy
气味让人头晕
Madam, you're still sick.
夫人，您还病着呢。
So there was no incense burning in the room.
所以房间里并没有烧香。
Is there no scent?
难道没有香味吗？
So why should I?
那我为什么要这么做呢？
Can you always smell it?
你能经常闻到吗？
No scent
无气味
I feel sick and confused.
我感到恶心和困惑。
Go get some sleeping pills.
去吃点安眠药吧。
Both oral treatment and aromatherapy
口服治疗和芳香疗法
It is recommended to purchase one with stronger medicinal properties.
建议购买药性较强的。
Why does the eldest lady suddenly want this?
大小姐怎么突然要这个？
i can't stand the pain
我无法忍受疼痛
It's best to take medicine and fall asleep
最好吃药然后睡觉
Remember to get more
记得获取更多
I'm afraid that in the future it will become so painful that I won't even be able to sleep.
我怕以后会痛得连睡觉都睡不着。
good
好的
It's time to go
该走了
I packed my bags.
我收拾好行李。
The 3 month period is approaching
3个月期限已临近
-I am now... -13 years ago
-我现在...- 13年前
A young girl I met at Hwangseongsa Temple
在皇圣寺 遇见的少女
Is that you?
那是你吗？
-Why are you suddenly asking this? - Is that you?
——你怎么突然问这个？ -那是你吗？
it's me
这就是我
How about the jade pendant I gave you?
我送你的玉佩怎么样？
Oh, it's you
哦，原来是你
It turns out it was really you
原来真的是你
Why didn't you tell me this whole time?
你为什么一直不告诉我？
I thought my uncle had forgotten a long time ago.
我以为叔叔早就忘记了。
I'm the only one who still remembers
我是唯一一个还记得的人
if you said
如果你说
If only I had told you from the beginning...
如果我从一开始就告诉你就好了……
So what if I say that?
那如果我这么说呢？
When we met again I realized something
当我们再次见面时我意识到了一些事情
It's you who keeps people thousands of miles away
是你让人们相隔千里
So I was under the illusion that I had admitted my mistake.
所以我有一种错觉，以为我已经承认了自己的错误。
Have we met somewhere?
我们在什么地方见过吗？
I found out about this later.
我是后来才知道这件事的。
However, due to the Zhong family's strict rules, this also affected my and my uncle's reputation.
不过，由于钟家家规森严， 这也影响了我和舅舅的名声。
How can I get it out?
我怎样才能把它取出来？
your father's case
你父亲的案子
let me check
让我检查一下
And I want to know how many lies Hua Qian told me.
我也想知道，花千骨到底对我说了多少谎。
Except what she admitted to me today.
除了她今天向我承认的事情。
There are a lot
有很多
Achen ‥
阿亨 ‥
Oh Chen, wake up
哦陈，你醒醒吧
Achen, I will never disappoint you in the future.
阿臣，以后我一定不会让你失望的。
Huaqian
华谦
At first you came to me pretending to be Mu Yao.
当初你是冒充慕瑶来找我的。
Then he secretly drugged me to force me to marry you.
然后他就偷偷给我下了药，逼我嫁给你。
Finally, they framed Mu Yao's family, along with your father, and were imprisoned.
最后，他们陷害了穆瑶一家，连同你的父亲，一起被关进了监狱。
From now on there will be a clean break between you and me.
从今以后，你我之间将彻底决裂。
Not relevant
不相关
Are you saying that this is a lax discipline in disciplining the children of Hwadu?
你是说这是对华都子弟的管教不严吗？
Or are you misbehaving yourself?
还是你自己行为不当？
What leads to better results but worse results?
是什么导致更好的结果但更差的结果？
Sister, don't be so nervous.
姐姐，别这么紧张。
I'm not asking about guilt, I'm just asking casually.
我不是在问愧疚，我只是随口问一下。
As far as I know, Hua Qian
据我所知，华谦
She can't see her senior at all.
她根本看不到她的前辈。
Another woman appears
另一个女人出现了
Not to mention asking another woman in front of my brother.
更不用说当着我哥哥的面问别的女人了。
Are you Hua Qian?
你是华谦吗？
It's really a ghost
真的是鬼
I can't sleep comfortably even in my dreams
即使在梦中也无法安然入睡
Am I that ugly?
我有那么丑吗？
I just had a nightmare
我刚刚做了一个噩梦
nonsense
废话
I hope my landlord will forgive me.
希望楼主能原谅我。
It's okay, you don't have to worry
没关系，你不用担心
Your mother was worried when she heard that you had been in a coma for five days.
你妈妈听说你已经昏迷了五天了，很担心。
He then asked me to bring in Dr. Wu to take a look.
然后他让我带吴医生来看看。
Senior is not here
前辈不在
To reassure mom earlier
为了早点让妈妈放心
I had to ask my doctor to come and take a look first.
我不得不先请我的医生过来看看。
I actually slept too long
其实我睡得太久了
I'm sorry, ma'am, please hold out your hand.
对不起，女士，请伸出你的手。
Hoegaju
回嘉州
The eldest lady's body was no longer seriously injured.
大小姐的身体已经没有重伤了。
It's just that the previous injury was pretty dangerous.
只是之前的伤势相当危险。
reach the heart
到达内心
I'm afraid my heart will hurt in the future
我怕以后我的心会痛
It's no big deal
没什么大不了的
Why was he unconscious for so long?
为什么他昏迷了这么久？
I just smelled a villain.
我刚刚闻到了一个恶棍的味道。
Did she use sleeping pills?
她用过安眠药吗？
great
伟大的
i am afraid of pain
我害怕疼痛
So I use this perfume to live my life.
所以我用这款香水来过我的生活。
Please forgive the villain
请原谅恶人
These are the three parts of the medicine
这是药的三个部分
There is a degree for everything.
凡事都有一个度。
The eldest lady is unconscious.
大小姐已经昏迷不醒。
I am concerned that the dosage of the medicine I am taking may be higher than the normal amount.
我担心我正在服用的药物剂量可能会高于正常剂量。
This will inevitably lead to weaknesses.
这将不可避免地导致弱点。
damaging to the mind
损害心灵
I hope you use it carefully, Mrs.
希望小姐姐谨慎使用。
Dr. for your reminder. Thanks Wu.
博士提醒您。谢谢吴。
I will definitely be careful in the future
以后我一定会小心的
I've never heard of it
我从来没听说过
Use this method to relieve pain.
使用此方法可以缓解疼痛。
I'm the weak one
我是弱者
I can't stand the pain
我无法忍受疼痛
So I made this decision
所以我做出了这个决定
go down
下去
yes
是的
Sister-in-law, do you want to kick me out?
嫂子，你想把我赶出去吗？
How can that be?
怎么可能？
House owner
房子的主人
actually
实际上
There's one more thing I don't understand
还有一件事我不明白
I would like to ask my sister-in-law for help in clearing my doubts.
我想请我嫂子帮忙解答一下我的疑惑。
House owner
房子的主人
I just woke up
我刚睡醒
my mind is still confused
我的思绪仍然混乱
- Or change the date... - It's no big deal.
- 或者改变日期... - 没什么大不了的
That day was an ancestral rite.
那天是祭祖仪式。
Assassin's Attack
刺客的攻击
The other ladies and ajummas were embarrassed.
其他的女士和阿姨们都尴尬了。
Daughter-in-law looks so peaceful
儿媳妇看上去很平静
It really catches my eye.
它确实吸引了我的眼球。
Because I trust my uncle
因为我相信我的叔叔
my uncle is next to me
我叔叔在我旁边
So I never panic
所以我从不惊慌
But I saw my sister-in-law take on an assassin
但我亲眼目睹了我嫂子与刺客的较量
Without flinching at all
毫不退缩
The aura actually made the assassins stop moving.
那气息，竟然让刺客们都停止了动作。
I just came out of the gates of hell
我刚从地狱之门出来
experienced a little fear
经历了一点恐惧
So my mind is a little unclear.
所以我的思路有点不清楚。
If you have anything to say, please let me know.
如果您有什么话要说，请告诉我。
you are doubting
你在怀疑
Was the assassination that day related to the Hua family?
那天的刺杀事件，与华家有关吗？
Daughter-in-law thinks too much
儿媳妇想太多了
I just asked casually
我只是随口问问
magistrate
地方法官
attentive
细心
House owner
房子的主人
Even though I'm just a backyard girl
尽管我只是一个后院女孩
but i know
但我知道
There is only one human life
人的生命只有一个
Even if you have bad intentions
即使你有恶意
I won't risk my life
我不会冒生命危险
Why did your daughter-in-law say this?
你儿媳妇为何这么说？
Today, the owner of the house brought a special doctor.
今天，屋主带来了一位专门的医生。
I just wanted to check it out for myself
我只是想亲自检查一下
Are my injuries fake?
我的伤是假的吗？
How is it going?
最近好吗？
The assassination happened suddenly.
刺杀事件发生得很突然。
The people behind it come and go mysteriously.
背后的人来来去去神秘。
No traces were left at the scene.
现场没有留下任何痕迹。
It's not just a whim.
这不仅仅是一时兴起。
It was already planned
本来就已经计划好了
There are only a few thieves
小偷只有几个
Didn't cause much of a fuss
并没有引起太大的骚动
Only a few family members were injured.
只有少数家庭成员受伤。
What about Zhongzhai?
中寨呢？
My uncle wasn't hurt.
我叔叔没有受伤。
There were no casualties among his guards either.
他的侍卫也没有伤亡。
What about her?
她怎么了？
Mr. Zhong was injured and lost consciousness.
钟先生受伤昏迷。
I don't know the specific situation.
具体情况我不知道。
Call the doctor and follow me to Zhongzhai.
叫了医生，跟我去中寨。
The matriarch and eldest princess is still waiting for news.
老太太和长公主还在等待消息。
Why not have the head of the household calm down the princess first?
为何不先让一家之主安抚公主呢？
good
好的
Please keep her watching.
请让她继续关注。
yes
是的
continued
继续
Thanks for watching
感谢您的观看